A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Press Materials FA1322
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Record Group 2, Accession 2018:088, 1953-2002; 2; 32.15 Cubic Feet 34 LTR size, 1 Half-LTR size, 40 LGL size, and 1 Half-LGL size Hollinger boxes
  - Press releases, 1955-1993; 1; 10.25 Cubic Feet 24 LTR size Hollinger boxes, 1 Half-LTR size Hollinger box, and 2 LGL size Hollinger boxes
    - Education and Culture Program subject press release files, 1956-1981; 1; 4.555 Cubic Feet 1 LGL size Hollinger box and about 10.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes
      - Philosophical Research Center Ford Foundation release - $332,390, 1974 January (Box 8, Folder 435)
      - Playhouse in the Park Ford Foundation release - $325,000 grant, 1969 September 12 (Box 8, Folder 436)
      - Portland Opera, undated (Box 8, Folder 437)
      - Princeton University Ford Foundation release - $700,000 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 8, Folder 438)
      - Princeton University Ford Foundation release - $22,000 grant for Design in America Conference, 1963 October 10 (Box 8, Folder 439)
      - Princeton University release - $335,000 grant to Council of Humanities, 1958 November 16 (Box 8, Folder 440)
      - Princeton University Ford Foundation release - $335,000 grant to Council of Humanities, 1958 October 13 (Box 8, Folder 441)
      - Print Club Ford Foundation release - $25,000 grant for Prints in Progress Program, 1963 June 13 (Box 8, Folder 442)
      - Pryce-Jones, Alan P. appointment Ford Foundation release, 1961 May 1 (Box 8, Folder 443)
      - Program for Playwrights and Resident Professional Theaters list of grants, 1975 September 30 (Box 8, Folder 444)
      - Playwrights Program Ford Foundation release - Grant to Center Stage (Paul Cherry), 1970 May 26 (Box 8, Folder 445)
      - Playwrights Program Ford Foundation release - Grant to Arena stage (Arthur Giron), 1969 September 12 (Box 8, Folder 446)
      - Playwrights Program release - Grant to Theatre of the Living Arts (Rochelle Owens), 1966 September 30 (Box 8, Folder 447)
      - Playwrights Program release Grant to Long Wharf Theatre (David Kranes), 1966 September 5 (Box 8, Folder 448)
      - Playwrights Program release - Grant to Alley Theatre (Paul Zindel), 1966 April (Box 8, Folder 449)
      - Playwrights Program release - Grant to Theatre St. Paul (Barry Pritchard), 1965 April (Box 8, Folder 450)
      - Playwrights Program Ford Foundation release - Announcement of program and grant to American Place Theatre, 1964 October 2 (Box 8, Folder 451)
      - Playwrights Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1960 March 9 (Box 8, Folder 452)
      - Playwrights Program Ford Foundation release - $100,000 grant and announcement of awards, 1959 March 10 (Box 8, Folder 453)
      - Playwrights Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1958 July 27 (Box 8, Folder 454)
      - Poets and Fiction Writers Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1963 September 16 (Box 8, Folder 455)
      - Poets and Fiction Writers Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1960 March 9 (Box 8, Folder 456)
      - Poets and Fiction Writers Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1959 August 20 (Box 8, Folder 457)
      - Purchase Program release - Works purchased from Whitney Museum, 1962 January 15 (Box 8, Folder 458)
      - Purchase Program release (see Visual Arts), undated (Box 8, Folder 459)
      - Purchase Program - Works purchased from exhibitions, circa 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 460)
      - Purchase Program - Works purchased from exhibitions, circa 1964 (Box 9, Folder 461)
      - Purchase Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, undated (Box 9, Folder 462)
        Note in original folder: For Copies See Visual Arts Program
      - Purchase Program - Sample information set, circa 1964 (Box 9, Folder 463)
      - Recording-Publication Program 1975 list of recordings and composers, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 464)
      - Recording-Publication Program 1971 list of recordings and composers, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 465)
      - Recording-Publication Program Ford Foundation release - Second program and initial, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 466)
      - Recording-Publication Program Ford Foundation release - $375,000 (initial), 1970 January 2 (Box 9, Folder 467)
      - Research Foundation of the City University of New York Ford Foundation release - $47,647 grant, 1970 October 2 (Box 9, Folder 468)
      - Roberson Memorial Center release - $200,000 grant, 1970 June 3 (Box 9, Folder 469)
      - Roberson Memorial Center release - $200,000, 1972 June-July (Box 9, Folder 470)
      - Rochester, University of Ford Foundation release - $10,000 grant, 1965 August 4 (Box 9, Folder 471)
      - Rochester, University of release - $10,000 grant, 1965 August (Box 9, Folder 472)
      - Reporters, Editors, and Critics Program Ford Foundation release - Second year awards, 1965 March 15 (Box 9, Folder 473)
      - Reporters, Editors, and Critics Program Ford Foundation release - First year awards, 1964 March 23 (Box 9, Folder 474)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - Grant to National Endowment, 1970 May 26 (Box 9, Folder 475)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - Grant to Arena Stage, 1970 May 26 (Box 9, Folder 476)
      - American Conservatory Theatre (ACT) Ford Foundation release - $800,000 grant, 1969 September 12 (Box 9, Folder 477)
      - Resident Theater Program release - $300,000 grant to American Conservatory Theatre (ACT), 1967 October (Box 9, Folder 478)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - $900,000 grant to APA-Phoenix, 1967 July 20 (Box 9, Folder 479)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - Grants to Minnesota Theatre Company and Center Theater Group, 1967 May 19 (Box 9, Folder 480)
      - Resident Theater Program release - Transfer of $500,000 grant to Center Theatre Croup, 1967 May (Box 9, Folder 481)
      - Resident Theater Program release - $535,000 grant to Mummers Theatre, 1967 March (Box 9, Folder 482)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - $245,000 grant to American Conservatory Theatre (ACT), 1967 January 31 (Box 9, Folder 483)
      - Resident Theater Program release - $250,000 grant to American Conservatory Theatre (ACT), 1967 January-February (Box 9, Folder 484)
      - Resident Theater Program release - $1.4 million grant to Alley Theatre, 1966 July (Box 9, Folder 485)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - $196,800 grant to American Shakespeare Festival, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 486)
        File also include an earlier release of a summary of recent Ford Foundation grants to theaters.
      - Resident Theater Program release - $60,000 grant to Stratford Shakespearean Festival, Canada, 1963 June 13 (Box 9, Folder 487)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - $6.1 million grant with summary and background sheets, 1962 October 10 (Box 9, Folder 488)
      - Resident Theater Program Ford Foundation release - $559,000 grant, 1959 December 1 (Box 9, Folder 489)
      - St. Louis Symphony Orchestra release - $50,000, 1973 October-November (Box 9, Folder 490)
      - St. Paul Opera release - $238,917 cash reserve, 1973 January (Box 9, Folder 491)
      - St. Paul Philharmonic Society release - $375,000 grant, 1973 November 21 (Box 9, Folder 492)
      - St. Paul Philharmonic Society release - $444,275 grant, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 493)
      - St. Paul Philharmonic Society Ford Foundation release - $96,500, 1970 May 26 (Box 9, Folder 494)
      - Salzburg Seminar FF release - $325,000 grant, 1970 June 28 (Box 9, Folder 495)
      - San Diego Opera, undated (Box 9, Folder 496)
      - San Francisco Ballet release - $926,291 cash reserve, 1976 March 5 (Box 9, Folder 497)
      - San Francisco Conservatory of Music release - $1 million, 1972 July (Box 9, Folder 498)
      - San Francisco Conservatory of Music Ford Foundation release - $41,000 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 9, Folder 499)
      - San Francisco Opera release - Opera by Carlisle Floyd, 1965 March 10 (Box 9, Folder 500)
      - San Francisco Opera release - "Blood Moon", undated (Box 9, Folder 501)
      - Santa Fe Opera (see Opera Association of New Mexico), undated (Box 10, Folder 502)
      - School of American Ballet brochures, 1976 August (Box 10, Folder 503)
      - School of American Ballet list of scholarship recipients, 1967 April 18 (Box 10, Folder 504)
      - School of American Ballet release - Regional Scholarship Program, 1960 February 19 (Box 10, Folder 505)
      - Seattle Opera Association, undated (Box 10, Folder 506)
      - Seattle Opera Association Ford Foundation release - $32,500 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 10, Folder 507)
      - Seattle Repertory Theater, undated (Box 10, Folder 508)
      - Settlement Music School of Philadelphia Ford Foundation release - $41,980 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 10, Folder 509)
      - Sheldon, Richard C. appointment Ford Foundation release, 1975 January 27 (Box 10, Folder 510)
      - Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music Ford Foundation release, 1972 July 21 (Box 10, Folder 511)
      - Society of the Friends of Nikos Skalkottas Ford Foundation release - $15,000 grant, 1970 October 2 (Box 10, Folder 512)
      - Southeastern Academy of Theater and Music release - $375,000, 1973 March (Box 10, Folder 513)
      - Spring Opera of San Francisco, undated (Box 10, Folder 514)
      - Stage/West, undated (Box 10, Folder 515)
      - Studio Arena Theater release - $418,643 cash reserve, 1976 February 20 (Box 10, Folder 516)
      - Studio Watts Workshop Release - $71,225 grant, 1969 April 9 (Box 10, Folder 517)
      - Symphony of the New World Ford Foundation release - $223,752 grant, 1970 October 2 (Box 10, Folder 518)
      - Symphony of the New World Ford Foundation release - $103,500 grant, 1968 October 11 (Box 10, Folder 519)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program Ford Foundation release, 1966 July 6 (Box 10, Folder 520)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program Ford Foundation letter and excerpt, 1973 February 1 (Box 10, Folder 521)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program Ford Foundation Letter/Special Report on status, 1973 February 1 (Box 10, Folder 522)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program releases from grantees (various), 1966 July (Box 10, Folder 523)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program Ford Foundation release - $85 million grant, 1965 October 22 (Box 10, Folder 524)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program Ford Foundation release - Grants to 61 orchestras, 1966 July 6 (Box 10, Folder 525)
      - Symphony Orchestra Program Ford Foundation release - $85 million grant, circa 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 526)
      - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 527)
      - Tamarind Lithography Workshop release - $705,000 grant, 1970 April (Box 10, Folder 528)
      - Tamarind Lithography Workshop Ford Foundation release - $56,925 grant, 1969 April 9 (Box 10, Folder 529)
      - Tamarind Lithography Workshop Ford Foundation release - $400,000 grant, 1962 October 4 (Box 10, Folder 530)
      - Tamarind Lithography Workshop Ford Foundation release - $900,000 grant, 1965 January 18 (Box 10, Folder 531)
      - Tamarind Lithography Workshop release - $165,000 grant, 1960 July 20 (Box 10, Folder 532)
      - Tharp Dance Foundation, Twyla release - $167,872 cash reserve, 1979 July (Box 10, Folder 533)
      - Theater - Ford Foundation support from 1957 through 1967 (Box 10, Folder 534)
      - Theatre Communications Group (TCG) release - $140,000 grant, 1980 March (Box 10, Folder 535)
      - Theatre Communications Group (TCG) Ford Foundation release - $374,000, grant, 1969 September 12 (Box 10, Folder 536)
      - Theatre Communications Group (TCG) release - Demonstration Unit, 1967 February 19 (Box 10, Folder 537)
      - Theatre Communications Group (TCG) release - $795,000 grant, 1964 November 30 (Box 10, Folder 538)
      - Theatre Communications Group (TCG) Ford Foundation release - $244,000 grant, 1961 March 20 (Box 10, Folder 539)
      - Theatre Genesis Ford Foundation release - $57,970, 1970 May 26 (Box 10, Folder 540)
      - Theatre Genesis release - $54,750 grant, 1968 October 6 (Box 11, Folder 541)
      - Toronto, University of Ford Foundation release - $8,500 grant, 1960 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 542)
      - Toronto, University of Ford Foundation release - $8,500 grant for university press, 1959 July 2 (Box 11, Folder 543)
      - Trinity Square Repertory Company, undated (Box 11, Folder 544)
      - Tulane University Ford Foundation release - $56,000 grant, 1962 October 4 (Box 11, Folder 545)
      - Tulane University Ford Foundation release - $75,000 grant, 1958 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 546)
      - Theater Design Program Ford Foundation release - Availability of the Ideal Theater catalog, undated (Box 11, Folder 547)
      - Theater Design Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1960 March 9 (Box 11, Folder 548)
      - Theater Design Program - Brief Descriptions of Projects included in "The Ideal Theater: Eight Concepts", undated (Box 11, Folder 549)
      - Theater Design Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1959 August 20 (Box 11, Folder 550)
      - Travel and Study Awards and other grants to individuals, 1977 August 1 (Box 11, Folder 551)
      - Travel and Study Awards and other grants to individuals, 1977 February 1 (Box 11, Folder 552)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1976 October 1 (Box 11, Folder 553)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1976 February 1 (Box 11, Folder 554)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1975 August 31 (Box 11, Folder 555)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1975 May 1 (Box 11, Folder 556)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1974 June 15 (Box 11, Folder 557)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1974 January (Box 11, Folder 558)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1973 May 1 (Box 11, Folder 559)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 December 15 (Box 11, Folder 560)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 September 1 (Box 11, Folder 561)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 July 21 (Box 11, Folder 562)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 July 15 (Box 11, Folder 563)
        The wrong date may likely have been written on the first two copies of the list.
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 June 1 (Box 11, Folder 564)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 April 15 (Box 11, Folder 565)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1972 March 1 (Box 11, Folder 566)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 567)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1971 June 4 (Box 11, Folder 568)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1971 April 12 (Box 11, Folder 569)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1971 January 26 (Box 11, Folder 570)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1970 December 8 (Box 11, Folder 571)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1970 October 18 (Box 11, Folder 572)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1970 August 24 (Box 11, Folder 573)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1970 June 24 (Box 11, Folder 574)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1970 April 28 (Box 11, Folder 575)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1970 February 19 (Box 11, Folder 576)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1969 October 21 (Box 11, Folder 577)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1969 July 23 (Box 11, Folder 578)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1969 April 24 (Box 11, Folder 579)
      - Travel and Study Program list of grants, 1969 March 26 (Box 11, Folder 580)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $366,000 grant, 1962 October 4 (Box 11, Folder 581)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $760,058 grant to 34 universities, 1962 February 14 (Box 11, Folder 582)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $760,058 grant to 34 universities and amount paid to each, 1962 February 14 (Box 11, Folder 583)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $310,191 grant to 35 universities, fifth year, 1961 January 26 (Box 11, Folder 584)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $310,191 grant to 35 universities and amount paid to each, 1961 January 26 (Box 11, Folder 585)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $1 million appropriation for 3 year extension, 1960 December 27 (Box 11, Folder 586)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $328,813 grant, fourth year, 1960 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 587)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $314,610 grant, third year, 1959 March 4 (Box 11, Folder 588)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $301,720 grant, second year, 1958 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 589)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $305,300 grants, first year, 1957 April 8 (Box 11, Folder 590)
      - University Presses Program Ford Foundation release - $1,725,000 appropriation, 1956 October 7 (Box 12, Folder 591)
      - United States Educational Foundation in Greece Ford Foundation release - $35,000 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 12, Folder 592)
      - Veterans Administration Hospital Ford Foundation release - $7,500 grant, 1967 January 31 (Box 12, Folder 593)
      - Virginia State College release - $85,000 grant, 1966 June 15 (Box 12, Folder 594)
      - Visual Arts Center of Alaska release - $250,000, 1974 March 14 (Box 12, Folder 595)
      - Visual Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Second year awards, 1960 February 1 (Box 12, Folder 596)
      - Visual Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Announcement of second year program, 1959 May 6 (Box 12, Folder 597)
      - Visual Arts, Program for Professional Training in - List of grants, Phase I and II, 1975 June 1 (Box 12, Folder 598)
      - Visual Arts, Program for Professional Training in the press releases to date, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 599)
      - Visual Arts Program Ford Foundation release - $1.5 million grant for 5 new programs, 1961 October 18 (Box 12, Folder 600)
      - Visual Arts Program Ford Foundation release - First year awards, 1959 February 18 (Box 12, Folder 601)
      - Visual Arts Program Ford Foundation release - $253,000 grant to American Federation of Arts, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 602)
      - Visual Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Announcement of first year, 1958 July 27 (Box 12, Folder 603)
      - Walters Art Gallery Ford Foundation release - $6,000 grant, 1967 January 31 (Box 12, Folder 604)
      - Opera Society of Washington, undated (Box 12, Folder 605)
      - Washington Theater Club Ford Foundation release - $250,000 grant, 1969 September 12 (Box 12, Folder 606)
      - Western Opera Theater, undated (Box 12, Folder 607)
      - Whatcom Museum Ford Foundation release - $10,000, 1970 May 26 (Box 12, Folder 608)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art Ford Foundation release - $155,000 grant, 1966 October 13 (Box 12, Folder 609)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art Ford Foundation release - $155,000 grant, 1966 September 27 (Box 12, Folder 610)
      - Working Theatre, New York release - $240,000 grant, 1976 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 611)
      - Working Theatre, New York - Announcement, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 612)
      - Writers, Program for Creative Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1959 February 16 (Box 12, Folder 613)
      - Writers, Program for Creative Ford Foundation release - Announcement of program, 1958 April 7 (Box 12, Folder 614)
      - Yale University (Yale Repertory Theatre) release - $506,586 grant, 1976 October 15 (Box 12, Folder 615)
      - Yale University Ford Foundation release - $150,000 grant, 1968 August 12 (Box 12, Folder 616)
      - Yale University Ford Foundation release - $80,000 grant for structural and acoustical research, 1966 July 19 (Box 12, Folder 617)
      - Yale University announcement of Museum Training Fellowships, circa 1966 (Box 12, Folder 618)
      - Yale University (see Curatorial Training Program - initial release), undated (Box 12, Folder 619)
      - Young Audiences release - $582,000 grant, 1964 November 18 (Box 12, Folder 620)
      - Young Audiences Ford Foundation release - $180,000 grant, 1959 December 1 (Box 12, Folder 621)
    - News from the Ford Foundation releases by date, 1966-1973; 2; .665 Cubic Feet About 1.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes
      Subseries contains a set of News from the Ford Foundation press releases. Unlike most of the press releases found in the previous subseries and in Record Group 1 Series 1, the releases in this subseries are not described individually. Instead, files in the subseries contain distinct runs of press releases that were published during a certain period of time.
      Many press releases in this series have the name Howard Dressner written on them. Dressner served as the Ford Foundation's Secretary and General Counsel. Perhaps, the entire set of press releases had been sent to Dressner. The underlined passages on many of the press releases may suggest that one or more individuals reviewed these documents.
      - Press releases, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 622-623)
      - Press releases, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 624-626)
      - Press releases, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 627-629)
      - Press releases, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 630-632)
    - Press job files, 1955-1993; 3; 4.65 Cubic Feet About 10.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes, 1 LGL size Hollinger, and 1 Half-LTR size Hollinger box
      Subseries contains more of the press job files that can be found in Record Group 1 Series 1. However, this subseries encompasses a larger amount of material and documents a broader period of time. Although there are job files in both record groups that have job numbers on them that could be used to identify and recreate a consistent system of arrangement, the files in this subseries are not ordered by those job numbers. Furthermore, this subseries contains files comprised of material other than records typically associated with a press job file. Such files document other aspects of the Ford Foundation's publicity and public relation work. For instance, there is a file that regards the Foundation's relationship with Burrelle's press clipping service, and another file that regards revisions to the Foundation's mailing list for its newsletter. The decision was therefore made during processing to not attempt integrating this material with the press job files in Record Group 1.
      - Mailing list - Maintenance/polling, general file, 1957-1979 (Box 14, Folder 633-634)
      - Mailing list - Maintenance/polling, various polls on Ford Foundation Letter, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 635-636)
      - Mailing list - Maintenance/polling, various polls on Ford Foundation Letter, 1961-1979 (Box 15, Folder 637)
      - Mailing list - Maintenance/polling, sample letters with polling cards, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 638)
      - Mailing list - Master indexes, press and general, 1955-1979 (Box 15, Folder 639-640)
      - 80-39. Turnabout for Distressed Housing, 1980; File includes two still images. Both are pictures of Ammel Park in San Francisco, California. (Box 15, Folder 641)
      - 80-34. American Classics, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 642)
      - 80-51. Prepaid legal service, 1980 May 15 (Box 15, Folder 643)
      - 79-78. Adult illiteracy, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 644)
      - 79-81. Strategic Arms Limitations Talk (SALT) memo to editors, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 645)
      - 79-74. Mississippi Action for Community Education (MACE)/Delta Foundation photograph exhibition, 1978-1982 (Box 15, Folder 646)
      - 79-72. American workers abroad, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 647)